[
    {
        "description": "Rational Numbers",
        "question": "After Performing which operations on whole numbers the result will always be a whole number",
        "answer": "Addition & Multiplication"
    },
    {
        "description": "Rational Number",
        "question": "Which of the following operations on whole numbers is associativity in nature",
        "answer": "Addition & Multiplication"
    },
    {
        "description": "Rational Number",
        "question": "Additive inverse of -51/100 is",
        "answer": "51/100"
    },
    {
        "description": "Rational Numbers",
        "question": "How many rational numbers are between 3/10 and 7/10.",
        "answer": "39"
    },
    {
        "description": "Rational Numbers",
        "question": "Find any three rational numbers between -2 and 0.",
        "answer": "-19/10 , -18/10, -17/10"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equations",
        "question": "Sum of two numbers is 95. If one exceeds the other by 15, find the numbers",
        "answer": "40 & 55"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equations",
        "question": "The difference between the two whole numbers is 66. The ratio of two numbers is 2:5. Find the two numbers?",
        "answer": "44 & 110"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equations",
        "question": "Aman is twice as old as Sana. Five years ago his age was three times Sana's age. Find their present age of Aman.",
        "answer": "20 Years"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equations",
        "question": "Deveshi has a total of Rs. 590 as currency notes in the denominations of  Rs.50, Rs. 20 and  Rs.10. The ratio of the number of Rs. 50 notes and Rs. 20 notes is 3:5. If she has a total of 25 notes, how many notes of each denomination she has?",
        "answer": "50 x 6 , 20 x 10, 10 x 9"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equations",
        "question": "A grandfather is ten times older than his granddaughter. He is also 54 years older than her. Find their present ages of grandfather and granddaughter respectively.",
        "answer": "60 & 6"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equations",
        "question": " Find the number of sides of a regular polygon whose each exterior angle has a measure of 45",
        "answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equations",
        "question": " Find the value of x: 2x – 3 = x + 2",
        "answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "description": "Quadrilaterals",
        "question": " The diagonals of a rhombus are ______of one another?",
        "answer": "Perpendicular and bisectors"
    },
    {
        "description": "Quadrilaterals",
        "question": " The perimeter of a parallelogram whose parallel sides have lengths equal to 12 cm and 7 cm is:",
        "answer": "38cm"
    },
    {
        "description": "Quadrilaterals",
        "question": "  If ∠A and ∠C are two opposite angles of a parallelogram, then:",
        "answer": "∠A = ∠C"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equation",
        "question": "What should be added to -7/3 to get 3/7?",
        "answer": "58/21"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equation",
        "question": "The age of the father is three times the age of the son. If the age of the son is 15 years old, then the age of the father is:",
        "answer": "45 years"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equation",
        "question": "Three consecutive integers add up to 51. The integers are:",
        "answer": "16,17,18"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equation",
        "question": "The difference between two whole numbers is 66. The ratio of the two numbers is 2: 5. The two numbers are:",
        "answer": "110 & 44"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equation",
        "question": " What is the appropriate condition to construct a quadrilateral?",
        "answer": " When four sides and one diagonal are given"
    },
    {
        "description": "Linear Equation",
        "question": "To construct a parallelogram we need to know:",
        "answer": "Two adjacent sides and one angle"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": " Find the square root of 6400.",
        "answer": "80"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": "Find the smallest number by which 9408 must be divided so that the quotient is a perfect square. Find the square root of the quotient",
        "answer": "3,56"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": "Which of the following is a perfect square",
        "answer": "625"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": "Which of the following will have 6 at unit place",
        "answer": " 24^2"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": "If 5278 is squared, then what will be at unit place",
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": "What will be the number of zeros in a square of 400",
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": " What is the sum of the first four odd natural numbers",
        "answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": "The sum of 1 + 3 + 5 + 7 + 9 + 11 + 13 + 15 + 17 +19 is",
        "answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": "The Pythagorean triples whose smallest number is 8:",
        "answer": "8, 15, 17"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": "Area of a square plot is 2304 m2 . Find the side of the square plot",
        "answer": "48 cm"
    },
    {
        "description": "Square and Square root",
        "question": "Find a Pythagorean triplet in which one member is 12",
        "answer": "12, 36, 37"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": "The one’s digit of the cube of 53 is",
        "answer": "7r"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a perfect cube",
        "answer": " 243"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": "By what number should 81 be divided to get a perfect cube",
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": "By what number should we divide 135 to get a perfect cube",
        "answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": " The value of 43√1000 is",
        "answer": "40"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": "Cube root of 15625 is",
        "answer": "25"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": " A perfect cube of a number having 0 at its unit place, ends with _____ zeros",
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": "Is 53240 a perfect cube? If not, then by which smallest natural number should 53240 be divided so that the quotient is a perfect cube?",
        "answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": " Is 1188 a perfect cube? If not, by which smallest natural number should 1188 be divided so that the quotient is a perfect cube?",
        "answer": "44"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": "Find the cube root of 8000",
        "answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": " Find the cube root of 13824 by prime factorisation method.",
        "answer": "24"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": "Is 243 a perfect cube?",
        "answer": "no"
    },
    {
        "description": "Cubes and cube roots",
        "question": "The ratio of speed of cycle 12 km per hour to the speed of scooter 36 km per hour is",
        "answer": "1:3"
    },
    {
        "description": "Comparing Quantities",
        "question": "The ratio of 10m to 10 km is:",
        "answer": "1/1000"
    },
    {
        "description": "Comparing Quantities",
        "question": "The percentage of 3:4 is:",
        "answer": "75%"
    }
]